<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title> - Status Update</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/tags/status-update/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/tags/status-update/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Announcing Laure Middleton as Acting Treasurer</title>
        <published>2024-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241118/"/>
        <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241118/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241118/">&lt;p&gt;GPEA Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to welcome Laure Middleton to the role of acting Treasurer, completing our volunteer Board.  She will serve as &quot;acting&quot; until the next election in 2025.  This position has been vacant since the departure of our previous president, and we are looking forward to what Laure can bring to the position.  As we engage in outreach and develop strategy, a full and active board helps to deliver more value to you, our members!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief introduction to Laure in her own words:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in Texas, I lived all over the country growing up mainly in Florida, Arizona, and Texas. After many years in the hospitality industry and culinary training, I found Urban Planning and studied as a non-traditional student at Texas State University in San Marcos, Texas. I love being part of the community development process and constantly learning and developing skills and my knowledge base. I firmly believe in collaboration and teamwork, and I am happy to serve the public interest. I am looking forward to serving on this Board and working with all of you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for stepping up to volunteer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
