<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title> - News</title>
      <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io</link>
      <description></description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/categories/news/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Listening Session on Thursday, June 26th at Noon in the Ridge Room</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250620/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250620/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250620/">&lt;p&gt;Hello Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time is fast approaching for GPEA to hold officer elections, as we are reaching the end of our current two-year term. We are announcing a Listening Session on Thursday, June 26th at noon in the Ridge Room to recruit candidates for the next election cycle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join us for a brief description of the four officer roles, and let us answer your questions about GPEA. Even if you do not want to be an officer, come and chip in your two cents. Meet the folks who will be running and make us work for your vote.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light snacks provided. Hope to see you there!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Parking Change Grace Period Request</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250418/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250418/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250418/">&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Memorandum&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;To:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mandy Hayes, Director of Human Resources&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;From:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Erik Rose, GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Date:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&#x2F;18&#x2F;2025&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Subject:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Parking Change Grace Period Request&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 17th, GPEA received notice from management of a change in parking accommodations, to occur on Wednesday, April 23rd, five business days after notice. This letter is a request to provide a notice period of seven business days, consistent with our agreement for members receiving notice of a change in workplace rules [19.2].&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our organization appreciates that management has provided an alternative parking option, in recognition that parking benefits are a significant element in the total compensation package of an employee, and a long-standing benefit within our workplace.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that many of our members feel obligated to park in the designated municipal lot, so that they do not impede residents trying to visit City Hall, or one of the many small businesses clustered along the nearby streets. Even when we are off-shift and walking to our cars, residents perceive us as representatives of the City government, and may resent us parking on the street when they cannot park in the municipal lot. Generally speaking, our members will park where told, which is why this is a change in workplace rules.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the alternative parking were more convenient, haste would be one thing, but the new location is farther away. This is an unpleasant adjustment for our career-oriented members, who fear that “temporary” parking could mean years. Given how long the current parking rules have been in place, we feel it is reasonable to request the full seven days notice, moving the transition date to no earlier than April 28th.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your careful consideration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Proposed Parking Benefit Reduction</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250416/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250416/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20250416/">&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Memorandum&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;To:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mandy Hayes, Director of Human Resources&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;From:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Erik Rose, GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Date:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&#x2F;16&#x2F;2025&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Subject:&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Proposed Parking Benefit Reduction&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue is regarding the upcoming vote of the City Council on the proposal to use the City Hall employee parking lot as a resting area. As a majority of GPEA members park in this lot, we feel the proposal constitutes a material change in employee compensation for our unit, and we would expect to meet and confer on this change, preferably as part of the normal bargaining process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loss in quality-of-life and convenience, above and beyond monetary cost, presents a significant burden relative to our current benefit. We are particularly concerned about impacts on the minority of our members experiencing mobility issues. With local crime rates spiking adjacent to the resting areas, it is difficult for us to tell our members that they will be equally as safe under the proposed change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parking benefit also has a market value. The City currently charges $240 for a yearly pass to park in the Redwood, Duck or Brown Bear lots, which is a reasonable proxy for the value of a parking spot. We view the loss of parking as equivalent to a $240 reduction in salary for affected employees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking is such a common benefit in the public sector that we have previously seen no need to raise this issue in negotiation. There is no specific language in the CBA detailing the parking benefit. However, this benefit remains a basic element of employee compensation. Long-standing members cannot remember a time &lt;em&gt;before&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; having this benefit, and incoming employees expect it as a part of their overall package.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to invite management to engage with GPEA on the subject of the parking benefit, so that we can resolve this issue together, rather than taking unilateral action outside of the bargaining process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Report on Insurance Meeting #3</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241120/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241120/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241120/">&lt;p&gt;Hello Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPEA representatives (Donna and I) attended the final insurance meeting with City management on November 12 at 2pm.  We discussed an alternative option to Willamette Dental Group offered by Pacific Source.  The additional cost was more than we were prepared to pay, so we elected not to move forward with the alternative option at this time.  We will continue to offer Willamette Dental Group as an option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the process, please reach out to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Announcing Laure Middleton as Acting Treasurer</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241118/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241118/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241118/">&lt;p&gt;GPEA Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to welcome Laure Middleton to the role of acting Treasurer, completing our volunteer Board.  She will serve as &quot;acting&quot; until the next election in 2025.  This position has been vacant since the departure of our previous president, and we are looking forward to what Laure can bring to the position.  As we engage in outreach and develop strategy, a full and active board helps to deliver more value to you, our members!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief introduction to Laure in her own words:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in Texas, I lived all over the country growing up mainly in Florida, Arizona, and Texas. After many years in the hospitality industry and culinary training, I found Urban Planning and studied as a non-traditional student at Texas State University in San Marcos, Texas. I love being part of the community development process and constantly learning and developing skills and my knowledge base. I firmly believe in collaboration and teamwork, and I am happy to serve the public interest. I am looking forward to serving on this Board and working with all of you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for stepping up to volunteer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Report from Oct. 9 Listening Session</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241030/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241030/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241030/">&lt;p&gt;GPEA Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first listening session on October 9th was a success, with eight members in attendance to talk collective bargaining and enjoy some light snacks.  After a short introduction, members did most of the talking while I wrote stuff down.  My thanks to James for helping to moderate, and kicking in out of pocket for the snacks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjects of interest identified by our members include:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 32-hour work week option.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education incentive for higher degrees (Masters etc.).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hybrid and work from home (WFH) options.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juneteenth recognized as a paid holiday.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular distribution of City-branded logo gear.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved access to comp time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out in your inbox for our email survey, and let us know what you think!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Report from Oct. 3 Insurance Meeting</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241003/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241003/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20241003/">&lt;p&gt;GPEA Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City management met with GPEA representatives and a representative from Hart Insurance to continue discussing upcoming insurance benefits for the year 2025.  Takeaways from the meeting for members:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employee costs are still on track to go down next year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providence will continue to be our provider.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pacific Source may be able to offer an HMO alternative to Willamette Dental Group that would continue to offer a lower-cost dental option while expanding access to more providers in town.  No specifics yet, but we have been vocal about expressing the difficulties our members have experienced accessing care through WDG, and this is a potential avenue for improvement.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the process, please reach out to Donna or myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Insurance Committee Meeting #2 on Oct. 3</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240930/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240930/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240930/">&lt;p&gt;Donna Anderson and Erik Rose will be representing GPEA members in a continuing series of discussions regarding insurance benefits for the upcoming year.  The meeting will take place at City Hall on Thursday, Oct. 3 at 3:30 pm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate those of you who have reached out to us regarding Providence as our choice of provider.  If you would still like your voice to be heard in the upcoming discussion, please contact one of our officers before the meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Listening Session on Oct. 9 at City Hall</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240917/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240917/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240917/">&lt;p&gt;GPEA Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be holding a listening session on 10&#x2F;9 (the second Wednesday of the month) from 12-1pm in the Ridge Room at City Hall. This is an opportunity to meet with your GPEA representatives, discuss the collective bargaining process, and to help us identify your priorities and values moving forward in negotiation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add to calendar: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;calendar.app.google&#x2F;KkvTZhx49yURstTC8&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;calendar.app.google&#x2F;KkvTZhx49yURstTC8&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Report from Sept. 12 Insurance Meeting</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240912/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240912/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240912/">&lt;p&gt;GPEA Members,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City management sat down with GPEA this Thursday (Sept. 12) to discuss upcoming insurance benefits for the year 2025. Donna Anderson and myself attended the meeting representing GPEA. Some good news that I can share is that employee costs appear to be trending downward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we are discussing continuing with Providence as a provider for the upcoming year. If you have any concerns about staying with this provider, please let us know. If you have had a negative experience, or encountered undue frustration, the time to address these concerns with our provider is now. Please do not divulge personal medical details, it is enough to tell us how the experience made you feel, and we will relay your concerns to management without bringing up your name.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to James, Donna or myself, by email, phone or in person. We want to hear from you as a member.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Erik Rose&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
GPEA President&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Executive Officers to Meet Sept. 11 at noon</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240908/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240908/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240908/">&lt;p&gt;The Executive Officers will be meeting at noon on Sept. 11 to discuss the upcoming meeting with management on the topic of insurance benefits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional topics include:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduling regular meetings for the remainder of the term.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduling an election date for the upcoming term.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Insurance Meeting Scheduled for Sept. 12</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240907/</link>
          <guid>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240907/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/news/events-20240907/">&lt;p&gt;City management has invited GPEA to participate in a meeting on Sept. 12 to discuss insurance benefits.  The president will be attending representing GPEA.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
